foreign
welcome to today's tutorial like this is
our second tutorial for ES net and for
this time we'll be firstly having a
warm-up session and then we'll be going
to the collab session that will be
having interactive jobs and showing how
we can add new jobs there and notice
that we'll be showing today how to add
new tasks and new models to our esgnet
and I'm detoshi and this is my email
so for today's agenda uh we will be
focusing majorly is on the why esdns can
support different switch tasks and that
will be continue to discuss what
components we need for new task in es9
but today's talk we'll be going through
the ASB spoof which is and has moving to
recognize whether the speech is a
synthesis or not so we'll be going to
the test can get briefly how the
mechanism is working for the as Facebook
and at last we'll be going to the collab
and going through the whole session
there and noting that you will be also
finished some like uh to fill some blind
into the original task so that you can
participate in the interactive jobs and
know how to add a new task from each of
the procedure
so before the talk I want to get your
attention there basically since we
follow almost the same installation
procedure of es net as Monday's tutorial
will be not going through that part
today and please start the collab early
and execute the like installation
procedures ahead of time and basically
you can start to do the clicks during
the first examination period which is
now and because like for the following
is we won't be going through that part
and that will be taking time so yeah it
will be better for you to start it early
and also today we'll be modified several
lines of source code which will be
potentially be lost when that case
disconnected from the collab therefore
like please try to save your
modification in a separate text file so
as to avoid losing them so basically we
will be having just a few lines Zone you
don't be worried like you have multiple
places to be added so that will be very
difficult to trace but I think basically
just a single text file will be fine but
we also recommend you going to rule like
with your own github.com only and Fork
it into your own space if you have the
experience in that but if you do not
have the experience that do not suggest
you to learn it now because we have the
other Focus for now so please just
follow in our procedure that is fine but
just simply in a separate text file
okay so in terms of yes United research
I can't listed some of the speech
processing texts there's like even more
than that but I think this is almost
like a most major Focus right now like
in the switch field and basically
including like the street recognition I
recognize your voice and like going to
the three sentences that try to like
convert the text into speech and doing
the voice conversion they're trying to
convert your voice into another
personalities and the speaker
recognition Long Jacket recognition to
recognize the speaker and language there
and speech emotion recognition speaker
diarization and so on and so forth so
basically in terms of that all the right
all the like the uh funds with the right
funds so basically it's showing that we
have already supported in the es net
already in terms of that for example the
street recognition synthesis conversion
emotion recognition diarization
enhancement and so on so basically all
of these tests are already supported yes
then there are still some missing plugin
which is also that we are quite
encouraged that you guys to be involving
in that so if you are interested in some
of the projects that are trying to solve
in the for example speaker recognition
spoken dialogue system that will be very
glad that you can join our team and we
can continue to the discussion and
notice that today's talk actually
today's tutorial is actually one of the
basis to like formulate those kinds of
new tasks into the ESF
so why esnet can support so many like
different formats of the switch task and
so on so for that purpose like basically
we are having a uniform design and
uniform like uh software design so
basically all the things can be
converted into a unified mathematical
form like which is from the sequence X
to sequence y from the transformation
app and in terms of that uh the escat is
a kind of acting as a two case in the
middle and in the X sequence we have the
speech texting speech and noise speech
well for the output sequence we have the
text speech and German text and clean
speech so when this input this speech
and output is text is clearly that uh
it's the ASR task like the speed
recognition test and if the input is
taxed and output speech we'll be having
the text to speech which is a synthesis
test and for the English speech and out
with German tax will be doing as a sleep
translation well for the other one like
knowing the speech and the clean speech
as the output will be getting into the
switch enhancement and separation and so
on
so in terms of that what component we
need for new testing yes then so in
short we kind of have two components
there like one is the task Library which
is the core procedure provided in the
task usually training and inference and
so on well for they will also have a
recipe session and we have the
recommended stage for the task usually
including data preparation formatting
purposes 3D inference and evaluation as
the major stages you have already had
the experience with the fourth tutorial
so I won't be going more details into
that but I think in general I could uh
it's kind of a recipe session will be
corresponding to a specific data set
then
in the letters fact we'll be continue to
discuss that uh
what in the text library and this is
also like what we will focus today
basically there will be four major
components that will be used primarily
like including the binary folder which
will be have the major entry of the
library set all the functions needs to
be using from here like in the ESL so
basically including the training
inference and sometimes with the collect
status and so on and in the other side
we also have the file IO which will be
uh presented as a input output stream
for different kinds of data like the
tags we have different kind of tags and
sounds and uh rttm is a rich format of
the switch input that will be noted the
speaker like the information and
something like that and there will be
also having some noisy to be encoded in
the rtdm and so on and for the other
side we also like intended to
incorporate the music structure like the
music XML and music Alexa mini style and
music something like that so this is
also our lucky in progress work
perfect other side like but the tasks
are like basically the major step here
is like to actually execute in the task
like the tuning of the host procedure so
the task is kind of uh like you usually
it's like a specific uh design for the
corresponding task for example if we had
ASR you can see that in the text folder
we have the asl.ty and we have the
sos.py which is for students over
synthesis we have the like the tds.py
which is the text-to-speech and for here
which which we will be focusing on as
with so we'll be having the as
facebook.py which is for the as we moved
up task here and later uh the cases that
also have the task name folder so for
example the ASR TDS STS iot IR which is
for that Edition and this is for the
task specific modules and their
corresponding loss calculations so
usually like we will be constructed the
computational graph from this test
folder for example ASR where we have the
encoder people the architecture which we
have to discussed in the Mondays
tutorial and for the later case that
there's also like many other folders
that won't be attached today but they're
also important but normally like we can
just keep it there so basically we'll be
using them for churches for using them
today but if you want to learn more you
can always like refer to our either the
web page we have the whole web page for
the toolkits and also like you can go to
the source code and basically there will
be also like many different information
contents in that
cool
so in the later space we also like have
the recipe session uh firstly we will be
having the explicit recipe for specific
purpose and we are attached that on
Monday so I will be skipped for today
but if you do not need to so basically
you do not worry about this today so
because we'll be we'll be touching that
but uh KB and I are already having a
tutorial on Monday so I think it will be
already enough and for the second part
we'll be having a template that includes
all the recommended stage for the
corresponding tasks so for today we'll
be preparing like 99 of it but need some
of your input to like make it uh
functioning and so on
but in general that that will be taking
all the stages so if you remember like
in the Monday's tutorial will be you'll
be having like the case like the for
example the clock stats and the format
with sap and speed perturbation and so
on then this sound formula that's
recommended stage in ASR tests and for
our specific text we'll be having design
specific test stages but here like for
today's talk specifically we're already
designing the variable come to make it
the simplest template so that you do not
need to worry too much about that but
it's still like a 400 lens so it's not a
very simple one so in general but it's
kind of already the simplest to be the
recommended stage in ESPN
so okay so for here we'll be going
towards the uh Cemetery text we want to
handle in that basically the speaker
verification and text moving test can
this is a problem kind of this concerned
like the basically Eastern actor
spoofing attacks from the human natural
speech and so here like the basic
concept is here like we have a speech
and there is real or fake and if we want
to kind of decide whether it's real or
fake so basically this is kind of
becoming very important the reason that
is because like you know like we have
the Deep fake in the speech area as well
like we can do the voice conversion that
can be convert US into the other words
and given that some ways can be used in
as the evidence for the for the core 10
also like some specific scenarios so
actually that will be very important for
you to distinguish like whether this is
a fake cut out if it's fake that we need
to like doing some other procedure like
we need to have more confidence to get
other evidence and so so it's very
important for nowadays
and in terms of the evaluation period
like we'll be focusing on the equal
average specifically and I won't be
going two details into that so if you
want to like go into the specific okay
why how it is calculated so on so you
can refer to this link and there's also
plenty of the material on the internet
so you can just Trace them and but for
here like uh I just want to let you know
that basically the lower the uh the
better like error rates right so
basically the lower method
okay so now we have more time for the
collect and any questions
cool so if we do not have other
questions we'll be going through the
collab today but notice that for now for
today we won't be going to details into
the collab record uh you use now black
Mondays version like we will be having
go through all the interactive jobs at
the time for this time we'll be just
telling you what you want to do for here
and later you are supposed to be using
like um I think it's 40 or 5 for 15
minutes right to be solving this uh
specific uh things and to making running
but notice that we will make it very
kind of trying to make it as easy as
possible so all the steps here is
already like only like a specific device
you need to modify to reach the ultimate
goal here
so firstly elected we have the
introduction and we also would like to
would like to thank uh yujang which is
like a PhD student at uh University of
Rochester and he actually has uh has a
lot like over the Hands-On tutorial and
sharing his knowledge and the specific
text which is the anti-smoving today
cool
and for this time as well like we'll be
having the checkpoints that you will
need to submit uh before the class
ending and at the at the same time like
there will be several like exercises
which is after the tutorial and you can
finish it later
and basically you can just submit the
PDF file like with your calculated
notebook to the criscope and which is
exactly the same format as the manual
tutorial so it's nice to have worried
about that
and for the objectives today like
basically after this tutorial you're
expected to know like how to add new
tasks in esnet2 and how to add new
modules in es92 and how to create the
new recipes of the template of a new
test from scratch so basically this
score is actually a bit ambitious
because ESN is so complicated but as at
the same time like it's also very
comprehensive to have different
components is to be making it working
for different functionality but for here
we'll be trying to make it as simple as
possible and by the same time we already
can Implement most of the codes for you
so basically you just need to fill a few
lines of the code but if you want to
learn more like basically you can go
into the uh our like comparison there
like what we're showing later and you
can know like the whole structure of if
you want to add a new test how did you
want to like doing that
and for the star please
executing this print date and time that
because that will be using for your
grading purpose
and for the installation specifically
almost like it's the same procedure as
your first tutorial so I won't be going
too much details over here I will be
skipping this today but but you are
expected to already run it during my
first explanation session
and here like this is for today's main
purpose that we want to provide you and
what you need to proceed over that and
we have provided most of the files you
need for the Asus Booth task so you do
not need to add any additional files
essentially but however notice that some
of the files have not come like complete
so I need your condition to proceed
oh sorry there's a typo here and for a
quick overview of the whole layout of
the new test you can just click this
link and I will be clicking this link as
well at the same time so you can have an
overview
so if you check this one you'll be
seeing that okay this is I have 50
changed files and with two thousand
lines but don't be afraid of that so
basically most of them are can be
essentially the same as the uh as the
other tests so if you want to create a
new test most of the lines you can just
copy and paste and that will be fine and
in terms of the different scenarios then
it will become different cases but I
won't be going too much details for this
page today we'll be going back to here
and basically as elaborated in the woman
novel and showing that there are like
two basic components for new tasks in
the ehlan which is a test library and
corresponding recipe setups and for the
following section we'll be briefly
showed overall layout of adding the Asus
both task in the es net and basically
the listed file are most of the minimum
requirements that the new test noted so
basically if you are watching at the new
tank this is kind of the basic
limitation here so you need to add all
the files at least most of the files
here to be adding for new tasks so here
like we are showing it in two folds
firstly that has February which is
located in the esc2 which is the second
version and already come we already kind
of expand that so basically we recommend
you now to focus on the esn2 version
and basically there is like the binary
folder as I know that like it's kind of
the main entry point that we get for the
specific task and what we also have as
with spoof which is the specific uh like
uh example of how to show in the whole
model here like basically the we can see
the decoder and mouse and we also have
the escm model which is a basic base
here I know that if you uh check that
basically we have the checkpoint for
attack 2.3 like as a like bracket uh
basically bracket as the following by
the specific files because it's kind of
showing that okay if you want to pass
this specific checkpoint you need to
modify this file to be make it completed
so that will make your life easier to be
accomplished that and for the later
spaces like the task part will be having
the whole like task initialization and
also model build up and so on training
and so on
okay so to help you understand more we
will recommend you to check out the
layout of other tasks as well like the
ASR ttsst and so I'm going to understand
how the code base is functioning but
here is the most the simplest one I will
say
and later in the recipe for ASP spoof uh
which is another side of the uh like the
complete uh I mean to complete the
recipe here like uh basically complete
the test here and we need to like have
the following which is a list of file
adding to the ESL as well like this is
the template and we have the ASB spoof
one and as facebook.shu something like
that and we have the es stand tutorial
here as well and okay so there's uh
actually there's an issue here like I
hope it changes very soon here so notice
that this is actually not from uh so
it's kind of separated so it is outside
of the template so it's not exactly the
stepping here well
and noted that because of the same link
like the Asus booth.sh for this one and
this one which we both want the
checkpoint one is essentially the same
for checkpoint two uh
and for the later stage we'll be doing
start with the ASP smooth data
preparation and as discussed in the
warm-up session is with school frames to
conduct a binary classification and as a
test layout it's a bit difficult to be
like uh compared to the ASR task we'll
be touching the here today to keep the
Simplicity we still use the exact same
file as the first tutorial which is the
web.sap text and other than to speaker
and speaker to authors and but on the
other hand we change the format of task
uh text into the author's ID plus one
and zero and this what zero means that
is actually the real speech and once
that is a fixed speed from the
synthesizer so which make it makes our
life quite easy so we can directly using
the format data and so on but if you
have different layouts probably you need
to change it a bit to be formulated into
your own structure so but that will be
making it quite difficult like in terms
of the layout to be using the existing
method from Cloudy so if you want to
learn more you can either check for
example the dilation recipe or the
street translation recipe and
essentially they are like output is not
the same as the normal ASR task so that
will be making some you know like a
hints of how to make such kind of tasks
to be functioning in our cases
and later we have the download data set
and basically this is a subset of the
Asus book 2020 to 2019 challenge here so
you'll be following that and to follow
to formulate the whole structure here
in terms of the prepared data will be uh
we already make the test template to be
simple as possible so the data operation
will be only two stages will be much uh
easier than the original task in the ASR
if you remember there there's also like
to build up the tokenizer and also you
want to build up that speed the
preservation over the time remove long
shot offices and so on but for here we
only have two stages that the first one
is the basic data preparation and
formulating the data into the structure
that we have defined here and also the
later cases is to try into like go
through the waveform add that to format
the web into our like a favorable like
structure
and later for the as with crack stats
which is come to the like the checkpoint
one
so similar to the previous tutorial like
we need to collect the statistics for
the data like not only for the back
sheet but also for the uh I mean getting
the overall like the global mean and
variance over the data so that we can do
the normalization later and basically in
this process like the data will be
passed into an iteratable like uh louder
so however like remember that the text
file is no longer the format as the ASR
recipe therefore we need to use another
data loader to allow the corresponding
information unfortunately we have a wide
range of data loaders for choices which
is listed here if you check here
cool yeah you can see that we have lots
of different uh like uh data structures
here
if you're seeing details and there's
like a key here which is a note that how
we can call this specific data types and
for each of the tabs we will be having
the like uh how this is kind of going
through the data like okay the audio
format tabs and like the Cloudy louder
and also like the text ins and what we
have the authors ID and with following
with that and also have to say
experience and will be authors at the
end which separated by comma so there we
have we already have like different
kinds of format right so here like uh
using this we can start to build up like
uh to choose like which correct format
and replace the replacement in the as
facebook.sh so the exact part we are
referring to is like the
yes so if you see the differences like
actually we have this whole files into
that and if you search for the
replacement
is so note that we already we have four
parts to be doing the replace me you'll
see that you can see here first one is
for the clock stats which is in the
stage three and we also have the later
two at the training as well
so sometimes I have the issue with for
example this have a actual black here so
which uh basically is because that you
can see that we basically by using the
calculation of the string over the uh
options here which is have a variable
here and notice that this variable is
essentially a string so in case that we
want to separate it out like different
uh options here we need to have an
actual space at the end so that we can
separate it out so if you can see like
we firstly have these options and then
later we use these options here and we
just using it as a string and if we have
this blank we can separate it out if we
do not have the black that will be
making the whole config to be connected
together like some of the string
database and name and tab will be
connected directly to the shape file and
that will be making the data not able to
be part part like passed into different
uh arguments and so on so we'll be
following this part we need to have
actual space here
cool
but here we won't we wait for you like
to be going through it now so we'll be
leaving some time for you to investigate
that but for now that will be continue
for the later cases and trying to
disgust the whole section here and later
you can fix like this part of your own
Okay so
after I finish this collect status we'll
be going through the modal parts and in
this section will be defined the as
Facebook model and use the model to
conduct the training of AIS with task
but either understanding here we will
first use the encoder to convert the
speech features into hidden
representation you then use the decoder
to conduct the classification and
firstly we are going to focus in on the
encoder part so this have a long history
over discussion of speech encoder in our
community and given the sequential
perspective people firstly imagine like
recurrent neural ranks record neural
networks and more recently we are
focusing on the conformal products we
should already like discussed on Monday
uh which is kind of basically an
extensional to the Transformer blogs and
in the previous setting we use a
Transformer blocks look like stats
however this time we will want to switch
it to the conformer
to make it happen so we basically want
to like using the already like a already
implemented conformer in the ASR part so
this is like a very a very good benefit
from using yes now so basically we have
the very good code result reusability
and in terms of doing that we already
support the performer Block in the ESR
part
so it is quite easy to import it into
the new task so in the es net adding
models that we already have having as
simple as two lines of code so please
add lines directly to here and I will be
showing the place uh like in this file
in this differences as well
oh
oh I see it's because that is it's not
there so I need to First be going to the
here right cool
from here you can see that we have the
to do here and basically will be firstly
you need to import it from the
confirmware Block encoder in which you
can follow the exact actually there's
already a example here so you can follow
here and we import the conformer block
and then in the later space
in line number 84 it will be at the
actual line and to make it a conformer
option and notice that the key here you
can see the key here is Transformer and
you can use conformer key as a key as
well for here basically you need to use
that because we already set up the
config file for that so it will be
recommend you to just use the
confirmware option here to make it
working
cool
and we'll be not waiting for you this
time as well like as I just explained so
basically we'll be continued for the
next section and we'll be having a lot
of time later so you can feel free to
debugging on your own and we can discuss
it like if you have any other questions
later
so later for the case like we are
targeting at the decoder here in this
stage where we finally start the
training as a previous tutorial you can
use the testable to monitor the process
you can execute this one to monitor the
process but if you do not want to do
that you can just skip this as well it
is it's just an optional like position
you want to do that so and for after
finish the thing holder we also need to
create a decoder to conduct prediction
and this that the encoder will be
generally hidden representation and we
want to add a simple decoder to conduct
overall hidden representation at the
time access and there will be another
linear layer to connect the model into a
binary classification task and basically
you need to fill the missing part into
this specific file and to finally start
the training for people who are not
familiar with the title which please
reference with the related resources
here like Pro you can basically you can
all this information should be enough
for you to build the linear decoder
noting that there's a final segment you
need to apply to the uh to the
prediction because that is very
important to be make sure that your you
use it they are predicting the like
probability to use the banner across
entropy laws in the package
so after that you'll be able to run in
this one I will be making it running so
this time we also go into the specific
Paradox so that is to show you that
where you need to add
so if you go to the linear decoder here
you'll be saying okay there we have like
a different to-do's firstly we want to
initialize a linear layer and then we
will be compute the mean over time
domain and then apply a projection layer
which is basically a linear layer we
defined here and later we'll be cut
change the like return value with
sigmoid function accordingly and as a
output cool
and given that we'll be going to the
other part so
firstly will be here going to the model
difference as the next section and for
this photo inference as the training is
finished we expected to conduct the as
Facebook on the test side and to
approach I will first you have to finish
the inference code base and for our text
specifically we need the log probability
of the prediction to compute the equal
error rate therefore the output should
be a float number for each artist and
please feel the missing parts with
to-doos here and so that will be
connecting the specific evaluation here
and if we go to this section
let me go to this section
s
okay so this is the file that we are
referring to and if you go to here you
can see that we actually have the to
those here note that this is for
exercise two so you do not need to like
fill the numbers here you just go into
this to this part and then this will be
fine together final result so notice
that this result is applied a sigmoid at
the last but for the final prediction
we're expecting to have a log
probability so it will be expected that
you'll after you get this uh probability
from the output you need to return a
float number and we Supply a exp to make
it like into the normal log probability
level sorry you need to apply a load a
log procedure to make it into the log
probability
cool
so later for the scoring so basically we
have already prepared the scoring
scripts for you so you can directly get
the ER by after finish all the previous
procedures and we'll be getting offender
without here
and I have a lack of feel it lies for
the uh like a Exodus here as well so in
the data you just don't know where I
already have like some extra data for
the training and please try to combine
them with the training set and then
conduct experiments with the
argumentative side you can also require
you to change the model configuration
basically if you achieve a better if I
already than the previous experiment you
can get the bonus Point here and which
basically is exactly quite similar to
the last time like the last tutorial we
have like we want we want you to build
that up like a set from scratch but
notice that basically this is quite a
little bit different from the original
ASR popular the data format is a bit
changed right
well for the access has two uh this is
because like one major issue for here
for the speech and test moving research
is the generation to unseen attacks so
notice that actually the training and
test that we have we are using like
specific as or original real speech and
also the synthetic speech from one of
the synthesizer but for the action for
the output specifically actually we are
hiding like different synthesizers which
is not the same as the training set so
exactly like we need to generalize that
to the Unseen text right so
um basically the sentences matter that
are not saying the trillion uh
anti-spoofing models in fact like for
here
the test set in our scenario is exactly
the same case recently there's like a uh
one case one class learning method that
compacts the newer like natural speech
representation and separate them from
the fake speech with a certain margin
and then the inviting space so we'll
actually have implement the am which is
like a generalized version of the one
class like soft Max here and we're
expecting you to like finish this whole
OC sub Max Plus and you can follow the
to see the information method but it's
kind of basically you can you need to
also change the config to make it like a
working internal training and if you
successfully implement the OC submit and
get similar battery or you can get a
bonus Point here
cool so this is uh the part of all my
talks for today and uh you're expecting
to finish all the like the in-class
checkpoint in this class later and thank
you very much and
so this is the question time